A Guide to the Russell Sage Foundation records FA015
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Russell Sage Foundation records, 1885-1983; 1907-1948; 1; 64.5 Cubic Feet 145 document cases
  - Programs, 1949-1980, undated; 5; 5.5 Cubic Feet 12.5 boxes
    - Developing the Social Sciences, 1955-1976; 1
      - Computer Time-Sharing Facility, H. Cline, 1967-1970 (Box 51, Folder 410)
      - Computer Uses in Social Science Research, H. Cline, 1967-1970 (Box 51, Folder 411)
      - Computer Uses in Social Science Research, H. Cline (a Follow-up), 1967-1972 (Box 51, Folder 412)
      - Critical Decisions by Doctors, D. Crane, 1969-1973 (Box 51, Folder 413)
      - Critical Decisions by Doctors, D. Crane, 1974 (Box 51, Folder 414)
      - Dartmouth College Conference on Social Science Time-Sharing Systems, H. Cline, 1968 (Box 51, Folder 415)
      - Nursing Role in Patient Care and Health Guidance, E. Brown, 1955-1976 (Box 51, Folder 416)
      - Pilot Study of Information Exchange and Questioning, L. Churchill, 1967-1970 (Box 51, Folder 417)
      - Social Science Frontiers, 1969-1976 (Box 51, Folder 418)
      - Social Science Statistical Computer Language Workshop, H. Cline, 1970-1971 (Box 51, Folder 419)
      - Survey of Black Social Scientists, E. Epps, 1970-1971 (Box 51, Folder 420)
      - "Survey of Black Social Scientists" (Final Report), 1971 (Box 51, Folder 421)
    - Deviant Behavior and Social Control, 1966-1969; 2
      - Bank Robbery, G. Camp, 1966-1969 (Box 51, Folder 422)
    - Education and Human Resources, 1968-1973; 3
      - Board of Human Resources, W. Kelly, 1968-1973 (Box 52, Folder 423)
      - Board of Human Resources, W. Kelly, 1968-1973 (Box 52, Folder 424)
    - Government, 1949-1980; 4
      - Analysis of Politics, Government and Administration of New York City, W. Sayre, 1955-1966 (Box 52, Folder 425)
      - Behavioral and Social Sciences, National Academy of Sciences - National Research Council and Social Studies Research Council, 1963-1972 (Box 52, Folder 426)
      - Center for Research (Urban), Regional Plan Association, 1965-1966 (Box 52, Folder 427)
      - Effective Use of Social Science Research in Federal Services, Social Science Research Council, 1949-1950 (Box 52, Folder 428)
      - Federal Utilization of Social Science Research, M. Graham, 1953-1955 (Box 52, Folder 429)
      - Government Statistics Program for New York City, A. Manvel, 1954 (Box 52, Folder 430)
      - Governmental Support and Utilization of the Behavioral Sciences, National Academy of Science - National Research Council, 1965-1969 (Box 52, Folder 431)
      - Impact of Government Programs on the Family, M. Sussman, 1964-1967 (Box 52, Folder 432)
      - Inter-University Seminar on Armed Forces and Society, M. Janowitz, 1967-1970 (Box 52, Folder 433)
      - Inter-University Seminar on Military Organization, February 3-4, 1961, M. Janowitz, 1960-1962 (Box 52, Folder 434)
      - Inter-University Seminar on Sociology and Military Institutions, M. Janowitz, 1962-1973 (Box 53, Folder 435)
      - Metropolitan Politics and Social Welfare, J. Greenstone, 1965-1974 (Box 53, Folder 436)
      - New York City Reorganization, Institute of Public Administration, 1965-1966 (Box 53, Folder 437)
      - 1960 Census Monographs, Social Science Research Council, 1949-1960 (Box 53, Folder 438)
      - Planning for Community Facilities, M. Myerson, 1954-1956 (Box 53, Folder 439)
      - Program in the Social Sciences, Institute for Advanced Study, Princeton, 1967 (Box 53, Folder 440)
      - Public Assistance Administration, A. Geddes, 1953-1955 (Box 53, Folder 441)
      - Seminar on Sociology and the Military, M. Janowitz, 1962-1970 (Box 53, Folder 442)
      - Social Science and Professional Military Training, C. Coates, 1956-1965 (Box 53, Folder 443)
      - Social Science in the Federal Government, Social Science Research Council (Washington Office), 1965-1968 (Box 53, Folder 444)
      - Sociology and the Future, W. Bell and J. Mau, 1966-1980 (Box 53, Folder 445)
      - Use of Social Science in Government, H. Cohen, 1964 (Box 53, Folder 446)
    - Health Services, 1958-1969; 5
      - Social Science and Medical Education, Stanford University, 1963 (Box 53, Folder 447)
      - Social Science and Medical Education, Stanford University, 1964-1965 (Box 54, Folder 448)
      - Social Science and Medical Education, Stanford University (Annual Reports), 1963-1966, 1969 (Box 54, Folder 449)
      - Social Study of a Children's Hospital, Boston, S. Croog, 1958 (Box 54, Folder 450)
    - Law and the Social Sciences, 1953-1979, n.d.; 6
      - District of Columbia Court System, Judicial Council of the District of Columbia, 1967-1969 (Box 54, Folder 451)
      - The Law and Social Science Program, B. Fasse, 1963-1979 (Box 54, Folder 452)
      - Pretrial Discovery and Adversary Process, W. Glaser, 1961-1968 (Box 54, Folder 453)
      - Research on the Legal Profession, J. Carlin, 1960-1965 (Box 54, Folder 454)
      - Residents and Fellows in Law and Social Science, B. Fasse, 1953-1976 (Box 54, Folder 455)
      - Review of Law and Social Science Program, Parts 1-4, 1975-1976 (Box 54, Folder 456)
      - Card File on Residency Program in Law and Social Science, undated (Box 54A, Folder 456a)
      - Card File on Residency Program in Law and Social Science, undated (Box 54A, Folder 456a)
      - Review of Law and Social Science Program, Parts 5-7, 1975-1976 (Box 55, Folder 457)
      - Training Program in Law and Behavioral Sciences, Columbia University, 1960-1965 (Box 55, Folder 458)
      - Training Program in Law and Behavioral Sciences, Yale University, A. Goldstein, 1965-1975 (Box 55, Folder 459)
      - Uniform Consumer Credit Code, National Conference of Commissioners on Uniform Small Loan Laws, 1967 (Box 55, Folder 460)
      - Uniform Legislation in Consumer Credit, A. Dunham and T. Hopkins, 1964 (Box 55, Folder 461)
      - Uniform Legislation in Consumer Credit, A. Dunham and T. Hopkins, 1965-1967 (Box 55, Folder 462)
    - Mass Media and the Social Sciences, 1964-1971; 7
      - Trans-Action Fellowships, Washington University, 1966-1971 (Box 55, Folder 463)
      - University of Wisconsin Journalism, C. Higbie and P. Hammond, 1964-1968 (Box 55, Folder 464)
      - University of Wisconsin Journalism - Enzer Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 55, Folder 465)
      - University of Wisconsin Journalism - Higbie Correspondence, 1965-1968 (Box 55, Folder 466)
    - Social Sciences and Human Biology, 1967-1977; 8
      - Administration of Studies on the Prolongation and Termination of Life, H. Freeman, 1968 (Box 56, Folder 467)
      - Center for Behavior Genetics and Evolution, G. Lindzey, 1967-1970 (Box 56, Folder 468)
      - Conference on Comparative Social Behavior, Smithsonian Institution, 1969 (Box 56, Folder 469)
      - Conference on the Legal, Economic and Social Aspects of Organ Transplant, B. Manning, 1968 (Box 56, Folder 470)
      - Conference on Student Drug Use, National Student Association, 1967 (Box 56, Folder 471)
      - Environmental Influences on Behavior, D. Glass, 1968-1971 (Box 56, Folder 472)
      - "Experimentation with Human Beings" Casebook, J. Katz, 1968-1977 (Box 56, Folder 473)
      - Impact of Dying Member on Family, A. Strauss, 1968-1974 (Box 56, Folder 474)
      - Impact of Dying Member on Family, A. Strauss, 1974 (Box 56, Folder 475)
      - Medical Care of U. S. Casualities in Vietnam, H. Freeman, 1968-1975 (Box 56, Folder 476)
      - Outline of Strategic Researches in Sociological Comparisons Between Humans and Infrahumans, W. Wallace, 1970 (Box 56, Folder 477)
      - Review Committees on Human Experimentation, R. McNeur, 1968-1975 (Box 56, Folder 478)
      - Social and Psychological Differentials in Combat Survival, R. Little, 1969-1970 (Box 56, Folder 479)
      - Social Factors in Irregularities in Dates of Death, D. Phillips, 1969-1970 (Box 56, Folder 480)
      - Social Science and Biology: A Developmental Program in Cross-Disciplinary Teaching and Research, L. Cottrell, 1967-1973 (Box 56, Folder 481)
      - Theoretic Framework for Comparisons of Social Phenomena Across Biological Species, W. Wallace, 1969-1970 (Box 56, Folder 482)
      - Training Appraisal and Planning Conference, Social Science Research Council Committee on Biological Bases of Social Behavior, P. Herring, 1968 (Box 56, Folder 483)
      - Values and Beliefs, Prolongation of Life, A. Knutson, 1967-1969, 1974 (Box 56, Folder 484)
      - Values and Beliefs, Prolongation of Life, A. Knutson, 1969-1973 (Box 56, Folder 485)
    - Staff Projects, 1967,1979; 9
      - Consequences of Ability Testing, O. Brim, D. Goslin, D. Glass, 1967 (Box 57, Folder 486)
      - Impact of Demographic Changes in Selected Urban Institutions, E. Sheldon, 1969 (Box 57, Folder 487)
    - Studies in Philanthropy, 1950-1978; 10
      - Analysis of Charitable Trusts, California I, W. Howland, 1959-1978 (Box 57, Folder 488)
      - Analysis of Charitable Trusts, California II, M. Fremont-Smith, 1964-1967 (Box 57, Folder 489)
      - Brandeis University American Philanthropy Project, C. Schottland, 1959-1963 (Box 57, Folder 490)
      - British Philanthropy, W. Jordon, 1958-1962 (Box 57, Folder 491)
      - Charitable Contributions of Wisconsin Residents, K. Lutterman, 1963-1967 (Box 57, Folder 492)
      - Conference on Altruism and Economic Theory, E. Phelps, 1971-1975 (Box 57, Folder 493)
      - Conference on Altruism and Economic Theory (Presented Papers), March 3-4, 1972 (Box 57, Folder 494)
      - Conference on Public Policy for Foundation Officials, Brookings Institution, J. Mitchell, 1969-1972 (Box 58, Folder 495)
      - Corporate Philanthropy, M. Fremont-Smith, 1966-1971 (Box 58, Folder 496)
      - Corporate Giving, F. E. Andrews, 1949-1951 (Box 58, Folder 497)
      - European Foundation Directory, 1970 (Box 58, Folder 498)
      - European Philanthropy, A. Gouldner, 1965-1970 (Box 58, Folder 499)
      - "Foundation Directory," F. M. Andrews, 1958-1965 (Box 58, Folder 500)
      - "Foundation Directory," Foundation Center, F. E. Andrews, 1962-1970 (Box 58, Folder 501)
      - Foundation Investments Study, Foundation Library Center, R. Nelson, 1954, 1961-1967 (Box 58, Folder 502)
      - Foundation Library Center Washington Office, 1963-1968 (Box 58, Folder 503)
      - History of British Philanthropy, D. Owen, 1956-1964 (Box 58, Folder 504)
      - Homer Folks Study, M. Curti and W. Trattner, 1961-1968 (Box 58, Folder 505)
      - Impact of Foundation Provisions on Tax Reform Act, J. Labovitz, 1967-1974 (Box 58, Folder 506)
      - Impact of Foundation Provisions on Tax Reform Act, J. Labovitz - Reports, 1971, 1973 (Box 58, Folder 507)
      - "Legal Instruments of Foundations," F. E. Andrews, 1957-1958 (Box 59, Folder 508)
      - "Legal Study of the Problem of Obsolescence of Dispositions for Charitable Purposes," A. Scott, 1957-1959 (Box 59, Folder 509)
      - Pan American Development Foundation, 1965-1969 (Box 59, Folder 510)
      - Pan American Development Foundation, "A Statement of the Laws of Uruguay in Matters Affecting Business", 1963 (Box 59, Folder 511)
      - Philanthropic Foundations, F. E. Andrews, 1954-1957 (Box 59, Folder 512)
      - Philanthropic Needs in Health, Education, Welfare and Cultural Activities, New School for Social Research, 1968-1971 (Box 59, Folder 513)
      - Philanthropy and the History of Foundations, W. Davies, 1950-1952 (Box 59, Folder 514)
      - Philanthropy: Historical Background and Current Trends (Annotated Bibliography), M. Otto, 1955 (Box 59, Folder 515)
      - Philanthropy in the American Economy, National Bureau of Economic Research, 1958-1961 (Box 59, Folder 516)
      - Philanthropy in the American Economy, National Bureau of Economic Research, 1962-1969 (Box 60, Folder 517)
      - Public Accounting of Charitable Trusts, M. Fremont-Smith, 1961-1967 (Box 60, Folder 518)
      - Risk Capital, R. Colvard, 1961-1965 (Box 60, Folder 519)
      - Secularization of Philanthropy, I. Weinberg, 1965 (Box 60, Folder 520)
      - Study of the Foundation Administrator, E. Hughes, 1968-1970 (Box 60, Folder 521)
      - Study of the Foundation Administrator, A. Zurcher and J. Dustan, 1967-1971 (Box 60, Folder 522)
      - Study of the Foundation Administrator (Interviews), R. Colvard, 1961-1962 (Box 60, Folder 523)
      - Study of the Foundation Administrator (Interviews), R. Colvard, 1961-1962 (Box 60, Folder 524)
      - Study of Philanthropy in New York City, R. Hamlin, 1968 (Box 60, Folder 525)
      - Survey of Philanthropy in Europe, S. Clough, 1958-1960 (Box 61, Folder 526)
      - Trusteeship and Management of Foundations, D. Young and W. Moore, 1966, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 527)
      - Typology of Foundations (Working Paper), A. Etzioni, N. Fainstein, and S. Fainstein, 1970-1971 (Box 61, Folder 528)
    - Studies of Social Change, 1966-1975; 11
      - Income Maintenance Evaluation, H. Costner, 1970 (Box 61, Folder 529)
      - Indicators of Social Change from Replication Studies, O. Duncan, 1970-1973 (Box 61, Folder 530)
      - International Statistical Institute, 1971 Meeting, 1970-1974 (Box 61, Folder 531)
      - Mathematical Studies of Social Violence, S. Spilerman, 1971-1974 (Box 61, Folder 532)
      - Monitoring Social Change, E. Sheldon, 1965-1969 (Box 61, Folder 533)
      - Moral Education and Reeducation in the Schools ..., L. Kohlberg and E. Turiel, 1970-1972 (Box 61, Folder 534)
      - Operation Exodus: Problems of Evaluation, J. Teele, 1970-1972 (Box 61, Folder 535)
      - Science, Technology and Social Change, D. Bell, 1966-1972 (Box 61, Folder 536)
      - Social Audits of Corporations, E. Sheldon, 1971 (Box 61, Folder 537)
      - Social Indicators and Social Aspects of State-of-the-Region Reporting, H. Perloff, 1972-1973 (Box 61, Folder 538)
      - Statistical Methods in Evaluation, M. Sheps, 1971-1972 (Box 61, Folder 539)
      - Survey of Research and Analysis Relevant to American Population Distribution, W. Thompson, 1970-1974 (Box 61, Folder 540)
      - Volume on Utilization of Sociology, P. Lazarsfeld, 1969-1975 (Box 62, Folder 541)
    - Residents, undated; 12
      Subseries 12 consists of correspondence and reports on the work of Russell Sage Foundation Fellows.
      - Carlin, Jerome E., undated (Box 62, Folder 542)
      - Carroll, James D., undated (Box 62, Folder 543)
      - Dubin, Gary V., undated (Box 62, Folder 544)
      - Evan, William M., undated (Box 62, Folder 545)
      - Gibbs, Jack P., undated (Box 62, Folder 546)
      - Glass, David C., undated (Box 62, Folder 547)
      - Goldstein, Joseph, undated (Box 62, Folder 548)
      - LeClercq, Frederic S., undated (Box 62, Folder 549)
      - Levine, Gene Norman, undated (Box 62, Folder 550)
      - Lipsitt, Paul D., undated (Box 62, Folder 551)
      - Raffel, Burton, undated (Box 62, Folder 552)
      - Swartz, Louis H., undated (Box 62, Folder 553)
      - Wiseman, Frederick, undated (Box 62, Folder 554)
      - Letters of Recommendation, undated (Box 62, Folder 555)
        Conditions Governing Access
        Restricted material.
    - Ford Foundation Grants, 1954-1964; 13
      Subseries 13 is correspondence and reports concerning use of grants provided by the Ford Foundation for Russell Sage Foundation-sponsored research.
      - Ford Foundation Grants, 1954-1964 (Box 62, Folder 556)
    - Declinations and Terminations, 1954-1955, 1958-1967; 14
      Subseries 14 contains a list of declinations and a chronological list of terminated projects.
      - Declinations and Terminations, 1954-1955, 1958-1967 (Box 62, Folder 557)
  - Marsh Island, 1911-1936; 6; 0.44 Cubic Feet 1 box
    Series 6 concerns the Russell Sage Foundation's donation of Marsh Island to Louisiana as a bird refuge and the Foundation's later attempts to have the island returned. The bulk of this series consists of lawsuit documents. The evidence material includes an affidavit by E. I. Broussard, fur sales statements, and publication notices and memoranda reviewing the situation.
    - History of Land Transfers, 1911, 1912, 1920, 1922 (Box 63, Folder 558)
    - Acts Establishing Wildlife Preserves, 1920 (Box 63, Folder 559)
    - Gordy vs. Maestri et al. and Jones vs. Maestri et al., 1930 (Box 63, Folder 560)
    - Petition for Bill of Injunction and Revocation of Deed, Nineteenth District Louisiana Court, 1931-1932 (Box 63, Folder 561)
    - Bill in Equity, U. S. District Court, 1932-1936 (Box 63, Folder 562)
    - Louisiana State Senate Bill 265, 1932 (Box 63, Folder 563)
    - Petition for Annulment of Deed, Nineteenth District Louisiana Court, 1933 (Box 63, Folder 564)
    - Evidence, 1912, 1920-1930 (Box 63, Folder 565)
  - Miscellaneous Reports and Proposals, 1967, 1972, undated; 7; 0.2 Cubic Feet 0.25 Box
    This series contains five reports or proposals on various topics. Four of them were written by either Orville Brim or Wilbert Moore.
    - "Diversity in Social Research Organizations," Brim, 1967 (Box 64, Folder 566)
    - "A Note on the Norm of Punctuality and its Violation by Academic Writers," Moore, undated (Box 64, Folder 567)
    - "Nothing but Praise for Your Proposal," Brim, 1972 (Box 64, Folder 568)
    - "Survey on Evaluation Studies of Social Action Programs", undated (Box 64, Folder 569)
    - "Work and Personality in the Middle Years," Brim, 1972 (Box 64, Folder 570)
  - Nova Institute, 1976-1980; 8; 0.3 Cubic Feet 0.75 box
    Biographical / Historical
    The Nova Institute, founded in 1976, is a nonprofit public service corporation that conducts analyses, surveys, and research for public and nonprofit organizations and the general public. Arnold Shore, Vice President of the Russell Sage Foundation, was on the Nova Board of Trustees during the period covered by this series.
    This series includes agenda and minutes, two annual reports, clippings, proposals, and reports.
    - Agenda and Minutes, 1977-1980 (Box 64, Folder 571)
    - Annual Reports, 1977-1979 (Box 64, Folder 572)
    - Clippings, 1977-1980 (Box 64, Folder 573)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1980 (Box 64, Folder 574)
    - Proposals, 1977-1979 (Box 64, Folder 575)
    - Reports (A-C), 1977-1978 (Box 64, Folder 576)
    - Reports (G-N), 1977-1980 (Box 64, Folder 577)
    - Reports (S-T), 1978-1979 (Box 64, Folder 578)
  - "RSF Bulletin", 1932-1948; 9; 0.5 Cubic Feet 1 box
    The Bulletin was an internal newsletter of staff and department activities.
    - RSF Bulletin, 1932-1948 (Box 65, Folder 579)
    - RSF Bulletin, 1932-1948 (Box 65, Folder 580)
    - RSF Bulletin, 1932-1948 (Box 65, Folder 581)
    - RSF Bulletin, 1932-1948 (Box 65, Folder 582)
    - RSF Bulletin, 1932-1948 (Box 65, Folder 583)
  - Personal Giving, 1879-1919, bulk 1906-1918; 1906-1918; 10; 18 Cubic Feet 41 boxes
    This series is divided into two subseries, as follows:
    Subseries 1: Institutions
    Subseries 2: Individual Legatees
    - Institutions, 1879-1919, undated; 1
      This subseries is arranged alphabetically by name. Within each file, the letters are arranged chronologically.
      Subseries 1 contains correspondence from institutions. Although the bulk of the series is letters, there are also reports on the activities of many of the organizations, clippings, publicity pamphlets and brochures, and photographs.
      - Adirondack Cottage Sanatorium, 1908-1918 (Box 66, Folder 584)
      - Albany Academy for Girls, 1908 (Box 66, Folder 585)
      - American Ambulance Hospital (Nurses' Fund), 1915 (Box 66, Folder 586)
      - American Association of Masters, Mates and Pilots, 1913 (Box 66, Folder 587)
      - American Bible Society, 1907-1917 (Box 66, Folder 588)
      - American Christian Literature for Moslems, 1916-1918 (Box 66, Folder 589)
      - American College for Girls in Constantinople, 1904-1909, 1911-1918 (Box 66, Folder 590)
      - American College for Girls in Constantinople, 1904-1909, 1911-1918 (Box 66, Folder 591)
      - American College for Girls in Constantinople, 1904-1909, 1911-1918 (Box 67, Folder 592)
      - American Female Guardian Society and Home for the Friendless, 1902-1918 (Box 67, Folder 593)
      - American Flag Association, 1912-1915 (Box 67, Folder 594)
      - American Forestry Association, 1912 (Box 67, Folder 595)
      - American Humane Association, 1912-1913 (Box 67, Folder 596)
      - American M. E. Z. Church (Sag Harbor), 1904 (Box 67, Folder 597)
      - American Mission School (Bombay), 1907-1908 (Box 67, Folder 598)
      - American Museum of Natural History, 1907-1916 (Box 67, Folder 599)
      - American Prison Association, 1910 (Box 67, Folder 600)
      - American Red Cross, 1907-1918, undated (Box 67, Folder 601)
      - American Sabbath Union, 1906 (Box 67, Folder 602)
      - American Scenic and Historic Preservation Society, 1907-1915 (Box 68, Folder 603)
      - American Seamen's Friend Society, 1900-1916 (Box 68, Folder 604)
      - American Seamen's Friend Society, 1900-1916 (Box 68, Folder 605)
      - American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1913-1917 (Box 68, Folder 606)
      - American Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals, 1905-1912 (Box 68, Folder 607)
      - American Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals (Lawrence, Long Island), 1908-1917 (Box 68, Folder 608)
      - American Sunday School Union, 1906-1918 (Box 68, Folder 609)
      - American Sunday School Union, 1906-1918 (Box 69, Folder 610)
      - American Tract Society, 1911 (Box 69, Folder 611)
      - American University Beirut, 1910 (Box 69, Folder 612)
      - Andrews, Mrs. J. J., 1912 (Box 69, Folder 613)
      - Anti-Saloon Movement (Lawrence, Long Island), 1909 (Box 69, Folder 614)
      - Army Relief Society, 1900-1918 (Box 69, Folder 615)
      - Art Commission of the City of New York, 1907-1915 (Box 69, Folder 616)
      - Associated Charities of Pasadena, 1910 (Box 69, Folder 617)
      - Association to Promote the Teaching of Speech to the Deaf, 1911 (Box 69, Folder 618)
      - Association for Relief of Aged and Indigent Females, 1907 (Box 69, Folder 619)
      - Astor, C. Augusta (Mrs. J. J.), 1885-1886 (Box 69, Folder 620)
      - Austrian Society of New York, 1907 (Box 69, Folder 621)
      - Babies' Hospital, 1900, 1909-1918, undated (Box 70, Folder 622)
      - Barnard College, 1906-1916 (Box 70, Folder 623)
      - Belgian Relief Commission, 1914 (Box 70, Folder 624)
      - Bellevue Hospital, 1914-1915 (Box 70, Folder 625)
      - Berea College, 1905-1917 (Box 70, Folder 626)
      - Berkshire Industrial Farm, 1909, undated (Box 70, Folder 627)
      - Berry Industrial School, 1888, 1904-1917 (Box 70, Folder 628)
      - Berry Industrial School, 1888, 1904-1917 (Box 70, Folder 629)
      - Bible and Fruit Mission, 1908 (Box 70, Folder 630)
      - Bible Society, 1916 (Box 70, Folder 631)
      - Bide-a-Wee Home for Friendless Animals, 1907, 1911-1912, 1915 (Box 70, Folder 632)
      - Birds of New York (Sage Collection), State Museum, 1914, 1916-1917 (Box 70, Folder 633)
      - Boston Women's Trade Union League, 1914, 1916-1917 (Box 70, Folder 634)
      - Bowery Mission, 1904-1905 (Box 70, Folder 635)
      - Boy Scouts of America, 1911-1918 (Box 71, Folder 636)
      - Boys' Club, 1916 (Box 71, Folder 637)
      - Bridgeport Neighborhood Club, 1905 (Box 71, Folder 638)
      - Bryn Mawr College, 1910 (Box 71, Folder 639)
      - Bryson Day Nursery, 1909 (Box 71, Folder 640)
      - Bundle Day Committee, 1914-1915 (Box 71, Folder 641)
      - Bundle Day Committee, Columbia University, 1915 (Box 71, Folder 642)
      - Camp Fire Girls, 1912-1917, undated (Box 71, Folder 643)
      - Catholic Charities, 1900-1918, undated (Box 71, Folder 644)
      - Catholic Charities, 1900-1918, undated (Box 72, Folder 645)
      - Catholic Charities, 1900-1918, undated (Box 72, Folder 646)
      - Chamber of Commerce, Committee on Commercial Education, 1914 (Box 72, Folder 647)